<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/ASIC_Monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/ASIC_Monitoring/</guid>
      <description>ASIC Monitoring Cumulus Linux provides an ASIC monitoring tool that collects and distributes data about the state of the ASIC. The monitoring tool polls for data at specific intervals and takes certain actions so that you can quickly identify and respond to problems, such as:
 Microbursts that result in longer packet latency
 Packet buffer congestion that might lead to packet drops
 Network problems with a particular switch, port, or traffic class</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/FRRouting_Log_Message_Reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/FRRouting_Log_Message_Reference/</guid>
      <description>FRRouting Log Message Reference The following table lists the HIGH severity ERROR log messages generated by FRRouting. These messages appear in /var/log/frr/frr.log.
   Category Severity
 Message # Message Text Explanation Recommended Action    Babel HIGH 16777217 BABEL Memory Errors Babel has failed to allocate memory. The system is about to run out of memory.   Find the process that is causing memory shortages and remediate that process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Monitoring_Best_Practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Monitoring_Best_Practices/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring Best Practices The following monitoring processes are considered best practices for reviewing and troubleshooting potential issues with Cumulus Linux environments. In addition, several of the more common issues have been listed, with potential solutions included.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Overview  Trend Analysis Using Metrics Generate Alerts with Triggered Logging Log Formatting  Hardware System Data  CPU Idle Time Disk Usage  Process Restart  Layer 1 Protocols and Interfaces Layer 2 Protocols Layer 3 Protocols  BGP OSPF Route and Host Entries Routing Logs  Logging Protocols and Services Device Management  Device Access Logs Device Super User Command Logs   Overview This document describes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Monitoring_System_Hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Monitoring_System_Hardware/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring System Hardware You monitor system hardware in these ways, using:
 decode-syseeprom sensors smond Net-SNMP watchdog  Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Monitor Hardware Using decode-syseeprom  Command Options Related Commands  Monitor Hardware Using sensors Monitor Switch Hardware Using SNMP Monitor System Units Using smond Keep the Switch Alive Using the Hardware Watchdog Related Information  Monitor Hardware Using decode-syseeprom The decode-syseeprom command enables you to retrieve information about the switch&amp;rsquo;s EEPROM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Monitoring_Virtual_Device_Counters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Monitoring_Virtual_Device_Counters/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring Virtual Device Counters Cumulus Linux gathers statistics for VXLANs and VLANs using virtual device counters. These counters are supported on Tomahawk, Trident II+ and Trident II-based platforms only; see the Cumulus Networks HCL for a list of supported platforms.
You can retrieve the data from these counters using tools like ip -s link show, ifconfig, /proc/net/dev, or netstat -i.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Sample VXLAN Statistics Sample VLAN Statistics  For VLANs Using the VLAN-aware Bridge Mode Driver For VLANs Using the Traditional Bridge Mode Driver  Configure the Counters in switchd  Configure the Poll Interval Configure Internal VLAN Statistics Clear Statistics  Caveats and Errata  Sample VXLAN Statistics VXLAN statistics are available as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Network_Troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Network_Troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>Network Troubleshooting Cumulus Linux contains a number of command line and analytical tools to help you troubleshoot issues with your network.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Check Reachability Using ping Print Route Trace Using traceroute Manipulate the System ARP Cache Generate Traffic Using mz Create Counter ACL Rules Configure SPAN and ERSPAN  Limitations for SPAN/ERSPAN Configure SPAN for Switch Ports Configure SPAN for Bonds Configure ERSPAN Selective Spanning Remove SPAN Rules Monitor Control Plane Traffic with tcpdump  Related Information  Check Reachability Using ping ping is used to check reachability of a host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Resource_Diagnostics_Using_cl-resource-query/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Resource_Diagnostics_Using_cl-resource-query/</guid>
      <description>Resource Diagnostics Using cl-resource-query You can use the cl-resource-query command to retrieve information about host entries, MAC entries, layer 2 and layer 3 routes, and ECMP routes that are in use. Because Cumulus Linux synchronizes routes between the kernel and the switching silicon, if the required resource pools in hardware fill up, new kernel routes can cause existing routes to move from being fully allocated to being partially allocated. To avoid this, monitor the routes in the hardware to keep them below the ASIC limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Simple_Network_Management_Protocol_SNMP_Monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Simple_Network_Management_Protocol_SNMP_Monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Simple Network Management Protocol (SNMP) Monitoring Cumulus Linux uses the open source Net-SNMP agent snmpd, version 5.7, which provides support for most of the common industry-wide MIBs, including interface counters and TCP/UDP IP stack data.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 History Introduction to Simple Network Management Protocol  SNMP Managers SNMP Agents Management Information Base (MIB)  Getting Started Configure SNMP  Configure SNMP with NCLU  Configure SNMP Manually  Start the SNMP Daemon Configure SNMP with Management VRF (used prior to Cumulus Linux 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Single_User_Mode_-_Boot_Recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Single_User_Mode_-_Boot_Recovery/</guid>
      <description>Single User Mode - Boot Recovery Use single user mode to assist in troubleshooting system boot issues or for password recovery. To enter single user mode, follow the steps below.
 Boot the switch, as soon as you see the GRUB menu. GNU GRUB version 2.02~beta2-22+deb8u1 +----------------------------------------------------------------------------+ |*Cumulus Linux GNU/Linux | | Advanced options for Cumulus Linux GNU/Linux | | ONIE | | | +----------------------------------------------------------------------------+  Use the ^ and v arrow keys to select Advanced options for Cumulus Linux GNU/Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Troubleshooting_Network_Interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Troubleshooting_Network_Interfaces/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshooting Network Interfaces The following sections describe various ways you can troubleshoot ifupdown2. Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Enable Logging for Networking Use ifquery to Validate and Debug Interface Configurations Mako Template Errors ifdown Cannot Find an Interface that Exists Remove All References to a Child Interface MTU Set on a Logical Interface Fails with Error: &amp;ldquo;Numerical result out of range&amp;rdquo; iproute2 batch Command Failures &amp;ldquo;RTNETLINK answers: Invalid argument&amp;rdquo; Error when Adding a Port to a Bridge MLAG Peerlink Interface Drops Many Packets  Enable Logging for Networking The /etc/default/networking file contains two settings for logging:  To get ifupdown2 logs when the switch boots (stored in syslog) To enable logging when you run systemctl [start|stop|reload] networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Understanding_the_cl-support_Output_File/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Understanding_the_cl-support_Output_File/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the cl-support Output File The cl-support script generates a compressed archive file of useful information for troubleshooting. The system either creates the archive file automatically or you can create the archive file manually.
The system creates the cl-support archive file automatically for the following reasons:
 When there is a core file dump of any application (not specific to Cumulus Linux, but something all Linux distributions support), located in /var/support/core</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/monitoring_system_hardware/network_switch_port_led_and_stats_led/Network_Switch_Port_LED_and_Status_LED_Guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/monitoring_system_hardware/network_switch_port_led_and_stats_led/Network_Switch_Port_LED_and_Status_LED_Guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Network Switch Port LED and Status LED Guidelines Data centers today have a large number of network switches manufactured by different hardware vendors running NOSes (network operating system) from different providers. This chapter provides a set of guidelines for how network port and status LEDs should appear on the front panel of a network switch. This provides a network operator with a standard way to identify the state of a switch and its ports by looking at its front panel, irrespective of the hardware vendor or NOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/network_troubleshooting/monitoring_system_statistics/Monitoring_System_Statistics_and_Network_Traffic_with_sFlow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/network_troubleshooting/monitoring_system_statistics/Monitoring_System_Statistics_and_Network_Traffic_with_sFlow/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring System Statistics and Network Traffic with sFlow sFlow is a monitoring protocol that samples network packets, application operations, and system counters. sFlow collects both interface counters and sampled 5-tuple packet information, enabling you to monitor your network traffic as well as your switch state and performance metrics. An outside server, known as an sFlow collector, is required to collect and analyze this data.
hsflowd is the daemon that samples and sends sFlow data to configured collectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/network_troubleshooting/using_nclu_to_troubleshoot/Using_NCLU_to_Troubleshoot_Your_Network_Configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/network_troubleshooting/using_nclu_to_troubleshoot/Using_NCLU_to_Troubleshoot_Your_Network_Configuration/</guid>
      <description>Using NCLU to Troubleshoot Your Network Configuration The network command line utility (NCLU) can quickly return a lot of information about your network configuration. Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 net show Commands Show Interfaces Troubleshooting Example: OpenStack Other Useful Features Install netshow on a Linux Server  net show Commands Running net show and pressing TAB displays all available command line arguments usable by net. The output looks like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/simple_network_management/using_nutanix_prisim_as_monitoring_tool/Using_Nutanix_Prism_as_a_Monitoring_Tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/simple_network_management/using_nutanix_prisim_as_monitoring_tool/Using_Nutanix_Prism_as_a_Monitoring_Tool/</guid>
      <description>Using Nutanix Prism as a Monitoring Tool Nutanix Prism is a graphical user interface (GUI) for managing infrastructure and virtual environments. In order to use it, you need to take special steps within Cumulus Linux before you can configure Prism.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Configure Cumulus Linux Configure Nutanix  Switch Information Displayed on Nutanix Prism Troubleshooting Enable LLDP/CDP on VMware ESXi (Hypervisor on Nutanix) Troubleshoot Connections without LLDP or CDP  Configure Cumulus Linux  SSH to the Cumulus Linux switch that needs to be configured, replacing [switch] below as appropriate:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/switchd_Log_Message_Reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/switchd_Log_Message_Reference/</guid>
      <description>switchd Log Message Reference The following table lists the log messages generated by switchd, organized by severity, then message text. These messages appear in /var/log/switchd.log.
    Severity Message Text Explanation Recommended Action    CRITICAL _port_group_config_values_get: hal_list_get failed on [str] List create failed. File a ticket with Cumulus Support.  CRITICAL _range_limits_get: start linux interface name buffer is NULL Invalid parameter. File a ticket with Cumulus Support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/troubleshooting_network_interfaces/monitoring_interfaces_and_transcievers_using_ethtool/Monitoring_Interfaces_and_Transceivers_Using_ethtool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/troubleshooting_network_interfaces/monitoring_interfaces_and_transcievers_using_ethtool/Monitoring_Interfaces_and_Transceivers_Using_ethtool/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring Interfaces and Transceivers Using ethtool The ethtool command enables you to query or control the network driver and hardware settings. It takes the device name (like swp1) as an argument. When the device name is the only argument to ethtool, it prints the current settings of the network device. See man ethtool(8) for details. Not all options are currently supported on switch port interfaces.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/understanding_cl-support_output_file/troubleshooting_log_files/Troubleshooting_Log_Files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/understanding_cl-support_output_file/troubleshooting_log_files/Troubleshooting_Log_Files/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshooting Log Files The only real unique entity for logging on Cumulus Linux compared to any other Linux distribution is switchd.log, which logs the HAL (hardware abstraction layer) from hardware like the Broadcom or Mellanox ASIC.
This guide on NixCraft is amazing for understanding how /var/log works. The green highlighted rows below are the most important logs and usually looked at first when debugging.
    Log Description Why is this important?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/understanding_cl-support_output_file/troubleshooting_the_etc_directory/Troubleshooting_the_etc_Directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/understanding_cl-support_output_file/troubleshooting_the_etc_directory/Troubleshooting_the_etc_Directory/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshooting the etc Directory The cl-support script replicates the /etc directory.
Files that cl-support deliberately excludes are:
    File Description    /etc/nologin nologin prevents unprivileged users from logging into the system.
  /etc/alternatives update-alternatives creates, removes, maintains and displays information about the symbolic links comprising the Debian alternatives system.
    This is the alphabetical of the output from running ls -l on the /etc directory structure created by cl-support.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>