<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_switches/Monitor_Switches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_switches/Monitor_Switches/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Switches With the NetQ UI, you can monitor individual switches separately from the network. You are able to view the various components deployed for all switches in the network. Being able to monitor switch component inventory aids in upgrade, compliance, and other planning tasks.
For network-wide monitoring, refer to Monitor the Network.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes&amp;hellip;
 Switch Inventory Card Workflow Summary View a Summary of Communication Status for All Switches  View the Number of Types of Any Component Deployed View the Distribution of Any Component Deployed View the Number of Switches with Invalid or Missing Licenses View the Most Commonly Deployed ASIC View the Number of Switches with a Particular NetQ Agent View a List of All Data for a Specific Component  Switch Inventory Card Workflow Summary The small Switch Inventory card displays:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/netq_ui_overview/NetQ_User_Interface_Overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/netq_ui_overview/NetQ_User_Interface_Overview/</guid>
      <description>NetQ User Interface Overview The NetQ 2.0.0 graphical user interface (UI) enables you to access NetQ capabilities through a web browser as opposed to through a terminal window using the Command Line Interface (CLI). Visual representations of the health of the network, inventory, and system events make it easy to both find faults and misconfigurations and to fix them. The UI is supported on Google Chrome. Other popular browsers may be used, but have not been tested and may have some presentation issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/ui_preface/UI_Preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/ui_preface/UI_Preface/</guid>
      <description>UI Preface A variety of resources are available for you to become familiar with Cumulus NetQ and to take advantage of its monitoring and analytic capabilities. These resources are identified here along with information about how the content is presented.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes&amp;hellip;
 What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus NetQ 2.0.0 Available Documentation Document Formatting  Typographical Conventions Note Conventions    What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus NetQ 2.0.0 Cumulus NetQ 2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>