<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cumulus Linux on Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>http://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cumulus Linux on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 13:28:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s New</title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/whats-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 13:45:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/whats-new/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus Linux 3.7.3 Cumulus Linux 3.7.3 contains a number of new platforms, features and improvements:
 New platforms include:
 Dell Z9264F-ON (100G Broadcom Tomahawk2)
 Edgecore AS7816-64X (100G Broadcom Tomahawk2)
 Edgecore AS7726-32X (100G Broadcom Trident3)
 Edgecore AS7326-56X (25G Broadcom Trident3)
 HPE SN2700M (100G Mellanox Spectrum)
 HPE SN2100M (100G Mellanox Spectrum)
 HPE SN2410M (25G Mellanox Spectrum)
 Lenovo NE0152TO (1G Broadcom Helix4) now generally available</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/cumulus-linux-index/Cumulus_Linux_Index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/cumulus-linux-index/Cumulus_Linux_Index/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus Linux Index  A
 aaa{.label} abrs{.label} abrs_stub_areas{.label} abrs_summary_lsa{.label} access_control_lists{.label} access_ports{.label} acl_policy_files{.label} acls{.label} active-active{.label} active_listener_ports{.label} addressing_interfaces{.label} algorithmic_longest_prefix_match{.label} alpm{.label} alpm_route_entries{.label} anycast{.label} aoc_cables{.label} api{.label} application_daemons{.label} apt{.label} apt-get{.label} area_border_routers{.label} arp{.label} arp_requests{.label} as_path{.label} asn{.label} asymmetric_routing{.label} authentication{.label} auto-negotiation{.label} autonomous_system_number{.label} autoprovision{.label}  B
 bestpath{.label} bfd{.label} bgp{.label} bidirectional_forwarding_detection{.label} bonds{.label} boot_recovery{.label} border_gateway_protocol{.label} bpdu_filter{.label} bpdu_guard{.label} brctl{.label} bridge{.label} bridge-ports{.label} bridging{.label} bridging_adding_interfaces{.label} bridging_ip_addresses{.label} bridging_routing{.label} btrfs{.label} buffering{.label}  C
 cable_connectivity{.label} cabling{.label} cdp{.label} centralized_routing{.label} cl-acltool{.label} cl-bgp{.label} cl-cfg{.label} cl-ecmpcalc{.label} cl-img{.label} cl-license{.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/installation-management/Adding_and_Updating_Packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/installation-management/Adding_and_Updating_Packages/</guid>
      <description>Adding and Updating Packages You use the Advanced Packaging Tool (apt) to manage additional applications (in the form of packages) and to install the latest updates.
Network Disruptions
Updating, upgrading, and installing packages with apt causes disruptions to network services:
 Upgrading a package might result in services being restarted or stopped as part of the upgrade process.
 Installing a package might disrupt core services by changing core service dependency packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/installation-management/Installing_a_New_Cumulus_Linux_Image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/installation-management/Installing_a_New_Cumulus_Linux_Image/</guid>
      <description>Installing a New Cumulus Linux Image This topic discusses how to install a new Cumulus Linux disk image using ONIE, an open source project (equivalent to PXE on servers) that enables the installation of network operating systems (NOS) on bare metal switches.
Before you install Cumulus Linux, the switch can be in two different states:
 No image is installed on the switch (the switch is only running ONIE). Cumulus Linux is already installed on the switch but you want to use ONIE to reinstall Cumulus Linux or upgrade to a newer version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/installation-management/Managing_Cumulus_Linux_Disk_Images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/installation-management/Managing_Cumulus_Linux_Disk_Images/</guid>
      <description>Managing Cumulus Linux Disk Images The Cumulus Linux operating system resides on a switch as a disk image. This section discusses how to manage the disk image.
For information on installing a new Cumulus Linux disk image, refer to Installing a New Cumulus Linux Image. For information on upgrading Cumulus Linux, refer to Upgrading Cumulus Linux.
Contents
{.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Determine the Switch Platform Reprovision the System (Restart the Installer) Uninstall All Images and Remove the Configuration Boot into Rescue Mode Inspect Image File Contents Related Information  Determine the Switch Platform To determine if your switch is on an x86 or ARM platform, run the uname -m command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/installation-management/Upgrading_Cumulus_Linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/installation-management/Upgrading_Cumulus_Linux/</guid>
      <description>Upgrading Cumulus Linux This topic describes how to upgrade Cumulus Linux on your switches to a more recent release.
Cumulus Networks recommends that you deploy, provision, configure, and upgrade switches using automation, even with small networks or test labs. During the upgrade process, you can quickly upgrade dozens of devices in a repeatable manner. Using tools like Ansible, Chef, or Puppet for configuration management greatly increases the speed and accuracy of the next major upgrade; these tools also enable the quick swap of failed switch hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/installation-management/Using_Snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/installation-management/Using_Snapshots/</guid>
      <description>Using Snapshots Cumulus Linux supports the ability to take snapshots of the complete file system as well as the ability to roll back to a previous snapshot. Snapshots are performed automatically right before and after you upgrade Cumulus Linux using package install, and right before and after you commit a switch configuration using NCLU. In addition, you can take a snapshot at any time. You can roll back the entire file system to a specific snapshot or just retrieve specific files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/installation-management/Zero_Touch_Provisioning_-_ZTP/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/installation-management/Zero_Touch_Provisioning_-_ZTP/</guid>
      <description>Zero Touch Provisioning - ZTP Zero touch provisioning  (ZTP) enables you to deploy network devices quickly in large-scale environments. On first boot, Cumulus Linux invokes ZTP, which executes the provisioning automation used to deploy the device for its intended role in the network.
The provisioning framework allows for a one-time, user-provided script to be executed. You can develop this script using a variety of automation tools and scripting languages, providing ample flexibility for you to design the provisioning scheme to meet your needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/802.1X_Interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/802.1X_Interfaces/</guid>
      <description>802.1X Interfaces The IEEE 802.1X protocol provides a method of authenticating a client (called a supplicant) over wired media. It also provides access for individual MAC addresses on a switch (called the authenticator) after those MAC addresses have been authenticated by an authentication server — typically a RADIUS (Remote Authentication Dial In User Service, defined by RFC 2865) server. A Cumulus Linux switch acts as an intermediary between the clients connected to the wired ports and the authentication server, which is reachable over the existing network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/Buffer_and_Queue_Management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/Buffer_and_Queue_Management/</guid>
      <description>Buffer and Queue Management Hardware datapath configuration manages packet buffering, queueing and scheduling in hardware. There are two configuration input files:
 /etc/cumulus/datapath/traffic.conf, which describes priority groups and assigns the scheduling algorithm and weights /usr/lib/python2.7/dist-packages/cumulus/__chip_config/[bcm|mlx]/datapath.conf, which assigns buffer space and egress queues
While it&amp;rsquo;s possible to change the buffer limits in the datapath.conf file, Cumulus Networks strongly recommends you work with a Cumulus support engineer to do so.
  Each packet is assigned to an ASIC Class of Service (CoS) value based on the packet&amp;rsquo;s priority value stored in the 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/DHCP_Relays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/DHCP_Relays/</guid>
      <description>DHCP Relays You can configure DHCP relays for IPv4 and IPv6. To run DHCP for both IPv4 and IPv6, initiate the DHCP relay once for IPv4 and once for IPv6. Following are the configurations on the server hosts, DHCP relay, and DHCP server using the following topology:
{height=&amp;ldquo;250&amp;rdquo;}
The dhcpd and dhcrelay services are disabled by default. After you finish configuring the DHCP relays and servers, you need to start those services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/DHCP_Servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/DHCP_Servers/</guid>
      <description>DHCP Servers To run DHCP for both IPv4 and IPv6, you need to initiate the DHCP server twice: once for IPv4 and once for IPv6. The following configuration uses the following topology for the host, DHCP relay and DHCP server:
{height=&amp;ldquo;250&amp;rdquo;}
For the configurations used in this chapter, the DHCP server is a switch running Cumulus Linux; however, the DHCP server can also be located on a dedicated server in your environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/Facebook_Voyager_Optical_Interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/Facebook_Voyager_Optical_Interfaces/</guid>
      <description>Facebook Voyager Optical Interfaces Facebook Voyager is a Broadcom Tomahawk-based switch with added Dense Wave Division Multiplexing (DWDM) ports that can connect to another switch thousands of kilometers away by adding transponders. DWDM allows many separate connections on one fiber pair by sending them over different wavelengths. Although the wavelengths are sent on the same physical fiber, they do not interact with each other, similar to VLANs on a trunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/Prescriptive_Topology_Manager_-_PTM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/Prescriptive_Topology_Manager_-_PTM/</guid>
      <description>Prescriptive Topology Manager - PTM In data center topologies, right cabling is a time-consuming endeavor and is error prone. Prescriptive Topology Manager (PTM) is a dynamic cabling verification tool to help detect and eliminate such errors. It takes a Graphviz-DOT specified network cabling plan (something many operators already generate), stored in a topology.dot file, and couples it with runtime information derived from LLDP to verify that the cabling matches the specification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/interface_configuration_and_management/Interface_Configuration_and_Management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/interface_configuration_and_management/Interface_Configuration_and_Management/</guid>
      <description>Interface Configuration and Management ifupdown is the network interface manager for Cumulus Linux. Cumulus Linux uses an updated version of this tool, ifupdown2.
For more information on network interfaces, see Switch Port Attributes.
By default, ifupdown is quiet; use the verbose option -v when you want to know what is going on when bringing an interface down or up.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Basic Commands ifupdown2 Interface Classes Configure a Loopback Interface ifupdown Behavior with Child Interfaces ifupdown2 Interface Dependencies Subinterfaces ifup and Upper (Parent) Interfaces Configure IP Addresses  Specify IP Address Scope  Purge Existing IP Addresses on an Interface  Specify User Commands Source Interface File Snippets Use Globs for Port Lists Use Templates Run ifupdown Scripts under /etc/network/ with ifupdown2 Add Descriptions to Interfaces Caveats and Errata  ifupdown2 and sysctl Long Interface Names  Related Information  Basic Commands To bring up an interface or apply changes to an existing interface, run:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/interface_configuration_and_management/switch_port_attributes/Switch_Port_Attributes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer1-switch-ports/interface_configuration_and_management/switch_port_attributes/Switch_Port_Attributes/</guid>
      <description>Switch Port Attributes Cumulus Linux exposes network interfaces for several types of physical and logical devices:
 lo, network loopback device ethN, switch management port(s), for out of band management only swpN, switch front panel ports (optional) brN, bridges (IEEE 802.1Q VLANs) (optional) bondN, bonds (IEEE 802.3ad link aggregation trunks, or port channels)  Each physical network interface has a number of configurable settings:
 Auto-negotiation Duplex FEC (Forward error correction) Link speed MTU, or maximum transmission unit  Most of these settings are configured automatically for you, depending upon your switch ASIC, although you must always set MTU manually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Copy_of_Prescriptive_Topology_Manager_-_PTM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Copy_of_Prescriptive_Topology_Manager_-_PTM/</guid>
      <description>Copy of Prescriptive Topology Manager - PTM In data center topologies, right cabling is a time-consuming endeavor and is error prone. Prescriptive Topology Manager (PTM) is a dynamic cabling verification tool to help detect and eliminate such errors. It takes a graphviz-DOT specified network cabling plan (something many operators already generate), stored in a topology.dot file, and couples it with runtime information derived from LLDP to verify that the cabling matches the specification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Copy_of_Spanning_Tree_and_Rapid_Spanning_Tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Copy_of_Spanning_Tree_and_Rapid_Spanning_Tree/</guid>
      <description>Copy of Spanning Tree and Rapid Spanning Tree Spanning tree protocol (STP) is always recommended in layer 2 topologies, as it prevents bridge loops and broadcast radiation on a bridged network. mstpd is a daemon that implements IEEE802.1D 2004 and IEEE802.1Q 2011. STP is enabled by default in Cumulus Linux.
The STP modes Cumulus Linux supports vary depending upon which bridge driver mode is in use. For a bridge configured in traditional mode, STP, RSTP, PVST and PVRST are supported; with the default set to PVRST.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Ethernet_Bridging_-_VLANs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Ethernet_Bridging_-_VLANs/</guid>
      <description>Ethernet Bridging - VLANs Ethernet bridges provide a means for hosts to communicate through layer 2, by connecting all of the physical and logical interfaces in the system into a single layer 2 domain. The bridge is a logical interface with a MAC address and an MTU (maximum transmission unit). The bridge MTU is the minimum MTU among all its members. By default, the bridge&amp;rsquo;s MAC address is copied from eth0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/IGMP_and_MLD_Snooping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/IGMP_and_MLD_Snooping/</guid>
      <description>IGMP and MLD Snooping IGMP (Internet Group Management Protocol) and MLD (Multicast Listener Discovery) snooping are implemented in the bridge driver in the Cumulus Linux kernel and are enabled by default. IGMP snooping processes IGMP v1/v2/v3 reports received on a bridge port in a bridge to identify the hosts which would like to receive multicast traffic destined to that group.
When an IGMPv2 leave message is received, a group specific query is sent to identify if there are any other hosts interested in that group, before the group is deleted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/LACP_Bypass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/LACP_Bypass/</guid>
      <description>LACP Bypass On Cumulus Linux, *LACP Bypass* is a feature that allows a bond configured in 802.3ad mode to become active and forward traffic even when there is no LACP partner. A typical use case for this feature is to enable a host, without the capability to run LACP, to PXE boot while connected to a switch on a bond configured in 802.3ad mode. Once the pre-boot process finishes and the host is capable of running LACP, the normal 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Link_Layer_Discovery_Protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Link_Layer_Discovery_Protocol/</guid>
      <description>Link Layer Discovery Protocol The lldpd daemon implements the IEEE802.1AB (Link Layer Discovery Protocol, or LLDP) standard. LLDP enables you to know which ports are neighbors of a given port. By default, lldpd runs as a daemon and is started at system boot. lldpd command line arguments are placed in /etc/default/lldpd. lldpd configuration options are placed in /etc/lldpd.conf or under /etc/lldpd.d/.
For more details on the command line arguments and config options, see man lldpd(8).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Multi-Chassis_Link_Aggregation_-_MLAG/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Multi-Chassis_Link_Aggregation_-_MLAG/</guid>
      <description>Multi-Chassis Link Aggregation - MLAG Multi-Chassis Link Aggregation (MLAG), enables a server or switch with a two-port bond, such as a link aggregation group/LAG, EtherChannel, port group or trunk, to connect those ports to different switches and operate as if they are connected to a single, logical switch. This provides greater redundancy and greater system throughput.
MLAG or CLAG?
The Cumulus Linux implementation of MLAG is referred to by other vendors as CLAG, MC-LAG or VPC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Spanning_Tree_and_Rapid_Spanning_Tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Spanning_Tree_and_Rapid_Spanning_Tree/</guid>
      <description>Spanning Tree and Rapid Spanning Tree Spanning tree protocol (STP) is always recommended in layer 2 topologies as it prevents bridge loops and broadcast radiation on a bridged network. STP also provides redundant links for automatic failover when an active link fails. STP is enabled by default in Cumulus Linux.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Supported Modes  STP for a VLAN-aware Bridge STP within a Traditional Mode Bridge  View Bridge and STP Status and Logs Customize Spanning Tree Protocol  Spanning Tree Priority PortAdminEdge (PortFast Mode) PortAutoEdge BPDU Guard Bridge Assurance BPDU Filter Storm Control Spanning Tree Parameter List Caveats and Errata  Related Information  Supported Modes The STP modes Cumulus Linux supports vary depending upon whether the traditional or VLAN-aware bridge driver mode is in use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Virtual_Router_Redundancy_-_VRR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/Virtual_Router_Redundancy_-_VRR/</guid>
      <description>Virtual Router Redundancy - VRR Virtual Router Redundancy (VRR) enables hosts to communicate with any redundant router without reconfiguration, running dynamic router protocols, or running router redundancy protocols. This means that redundant routers will respond to Address Resolution Protocol (ARP) requests from hosts. Routers are configured to respond in an identical manner, but if one fails, the other redundant routers will continue to respond, leaving the hosts with the impression that nothing has changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/bonding_link_aggregation/Bonding_-_Link_Aggregation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/bonding_link_aggregation/Bonding_-_Link_Aggregation/</guid>
      <description>Bonding - Link Aggregation Linux bonding provides a method for aggregating multiple network interfaces (slaves) into a single logical bonded interface (bond). Cumulus Linux supports two bonding modes:
 IEEE 802.3ad link aggregation mode, which allows one or more links to be aggregated together to form a link aggregation group (LAG), so that a media access control (MAC) client can treat the link aggregation group as if it were a single link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/ethernet_bridging_vlans/Traditional_Bridge_Mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/ethernet_bridging_vlans/Traditional_Bridge_Mode/</guid>
      <description>Traditional Bridge Mode Cumulus Networks recommends you use a VLAN-aware bridge on your switch. You use traditional mode bridges only if you need to run more than one bridge on the switch or if you need to use PVSTP+.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Create a Traditional Mode Bridge  Configure a Traditional Bridge with NCLU Manually Configure a Traditional Mode Bridge  Trunks in Traditional Bridge Mode  Trunk Example VLAN Tagging Examples Configure ARP Timers  Caveats  Create a Traditional Mode Bridge You can configure a traditional mode bridge either using NCLU or manually editing the /etc/network/interfaces file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/ethernet_bridging_vlans/VLAN-aware_Bridge_Mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/ethernet_bridging_vlans/VLAN-aware_Bridge_Mode/</guid>
      <description>VLAN-aware Bridge Mode The Cumulus Linux bridge driver supports two configuration modes, one that is VLAN-aware, and one that follows a more traditional Linux bridge model.
For traditional Linux bridges, the kernel supports VLANs in the form of VLAN subinterfaces. Enabling bridging on multiple VLANs means configuring a bridge for each VLAN and, for each member port on a bridge, creating one or more VLAN subinterfaces out of that port.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/ethernet_bridging_vlans/VLAN_Tagging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/ethernet_bridging_vlans/VLAN_Tagging/</guid>
      <description>VLAN Tagging This topic shows two examples of VLAN tagging, one basic and one more advanced. They both demonstrate the streamlined interface configuration from ifupdown2.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 VLAN Tagging, a Basic Example VLAN Tagging, an Advanced Example VLAN Translation  VLAN Tagging, a Basic Example A simple configuration demonstrating VLAN tagging involves two hosts connected to a switch.
{width=&amp;ldquo;300&amp;rdquo;}  *host1* connects to swp1 with both untagged frames and with 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/link_layer_discovery_protocol/voice_vlan/Voice_VLAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/link_layer_discovery_protocol/voice_vlan/Voice_VLAN/</guid>
      <description>Voice VLAN In Cumulus Linux, a voice VLAN is a VLAN dedicated to voice traffic on a switch port. However, the term can mean different things to different vendors. Voice VLAN is part of a trunk port with 2 VLANs that comprises either:
 Native VLAN, which carries both data and voice traffic, or Voice VLAN, which carries the voice traffic, and a data or native VLAN, which carries the data traffic in a trunk port.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/virtual_router_redundancy/ifplugd/ifplugd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer2/virtual_router_redundancy/ifplugd/ifplugd/</guid>
      <description>ifplugd ifplugd is an Ethernet link-state monitoring daemon, that can execute user-specified scripts to configure an Ethernet device when a cable is plugged in, or automatically unconfigure it when a cable is removed.
Follow the steps below to install and configure the ifplugd daemon.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Install ifplugd Configure ifplugd Caveats and Errata  Install ifplugd  Update the switch before installing the daemon:
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo -E apt-get update Install the ifplugd package:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Address_Resolution_Protocol_-_ARP/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Address_Resolution_Protocol_-_ARP/</guid>
      <description>Address Resolution Protocol - ARP Address Resolution Protocol (ARP) is a communication protocol used for discovering the link layer address, such as a MAC address, associated with a given network layer address. ARP is defined by RFC 826. The Cumulus Linux ARP implementation differs from standard Debian Linux ARP behavior in a few ways because Cumulus Linux is an operating system for routers/switches rather than servers. This chapter describes the differences in ARP behavior, why the changes were made, where the changes were implemented, and how to change port-specific values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Bidirectional_Forwarding_Detection_-_BFD/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Bidirectional_Forwarding_Detection_-_BFD/</guid>
      <description>Bidirectional Forwarding Detection - BFD Bidirectional Forwarding Detection (BFD) provides low overhead and rapid detection of failures in the paths between two network devices. It provides a unified mechanism for link detection over all media and protocol layers. Use BFD to detect failures for IPv4 and IPv6 single or multihop paths between any two network devices, including unidirectional path failure detection.
Cumulus Linux does not support demand mode in BFD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Border_Gateway_Protocol_-_BGP/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Border_Gateway_Protocol_-_BGP/</guid>
      <description>Border Gateway Protocol - BGP BGP is the routing protocol that runs the Internet. It is an increasingly popular protocol for use in the data center as it lends itself well to the rich interconnections in a Clos topology. Specifically, BGP:
 Does not require the routing state to be periodically refreshed, unlike OSPF. Is less chatty than its link-state siblings. For example, a link or node transition can result in a bestpath change, causing BGP to send updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Configuring_FRRouting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Configuring_FRRouting/</guid>
      <description>Configuring FRRouting This section provides an overview of configuring FRRouting, the routing software package that provides a suite of routing protocols so you can configure routing on your switch.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Configure FRRouting  Enable and Start FRRouting Integrated Configurations Restore the Default Configuration  Interface IP Addresses and VRFs FRRouting vtysh Modal CLI Reload the FRRouting Configuration FRR Logging Caveats  Obfuscated Passwords Duplicate Hostnames  Related Information  Configure FRRouting FRRouting does not start by default in Cumulus Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Equal_Cost_Multipath_Load_Sharing_-_Hardware_ECMP/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Equal_Cost_Multipath_Load_Sharing_-_Hardware_ECMP/</guid>
      <description>Equal Cost Multipath Load Sharing - Hardware ECMP Cumulus Linux supports hardware-based equal cost multipath (ECMP) load sharing. ECMP is enabled by default in Cumulus Linux. Load sharing occurs automatically for all routes with multiple next hops installed. ECMP load sharing supports both IPv4 and IPv6 routes.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Equal Cost Routing ECMP Hashing  Use cl-ecmpcalc to Determine the Hash Result cl-ecmpcalc Limitations ECMP Hash Buckets Configure a Hash Seed to Avoid Hash Polarization  Resilient Hashing  Resilient Hash Buckets Remove Next Hops Add Next Hops Configure Resilient Hashing   Equal Cost Routing ECMP operates only on equal cost routes in the Linux routing table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/FRRouting_Overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/FRRouting_Overview/</guid>
      <description>FRRouting Overview Cumulus Linux uses FRRouting to provide the routing protocols for dynamic routing. FRRouting provides many routing protocols, of which Cumulus Linux supports the following:
 Open Shortest Path First (v2 and v3) Border Gateway Protocol  Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Architecture About zebra Related Information  Architecture {height=&amp;ldquo;250&amp;rdquo;}
As shown in the figure above, the FRRouting suite consists of various protocol-specific daemons and a protocol-independent daemon called zebra.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/GRE_Tunneling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/GRE_Tunneling/</guid>
      <description>GRE Tunneling Early Access Feature
GRE Tunneling is an early access feature.
Generic Routing Encapsulation (GRE) is a tunneling protocol that encapsulates network layer protocols inside virtual point-to-point links over an Internet Protocol network. The two endpoints are identified by the tunnel source and tunnel destination addresses at each endpoint.
GRE packets travel directly between the two endpoints through a virtual tunnel. As a packet comes across other routers, there is no interaction with its payload; the routers only parse the outer IP packet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Introduction_to_Routing_Protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Introduction_to_Routing_Protocols/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Routing Protocols This chapter discusses the various routing protocols, and how to configure them.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Routing Protocols Configure Routing Protocols Protocol Tuning  Routing Protocols A routing protocol dynamically computes reachability between various end points. This enables communication to work around link and node failures, and additions and withdrawals of various addresses.
IP routing protocols are typically distributed; that is, an instance of the routing protocol runs on each of the routers in a network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Management_VRF/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Management_VRF/</guid>
      <description>Management VRF *Management VRF* is a subset of VRF (virtual routing tables and forwarding) and provides a separation between the out-of-band management network and the in-band data plane network. For all VRFs, the main routing table is the default table for all of the data plane switch ports. With management VRF, a second table, mgmt, is used for routing through the Ethernet ports of the switch. The mgmt name is special cased to identify the management VRF from a data plane VRF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Network_Topology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Network_Topology/</guid>
      <description>Network Topology In computer networks, topology refers to the structure of interconnecting various nodes. Some commonly used topologies in networks are star, hub and spoke, leaf and spine, and broadcast.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Clos Topologies Over-Subscribed and Non-Blocking Configurations Containing the Failure Domain Load Balancing  Clos Topologies In the vast majority of modern data centers, Clos or fat tree topology is very popular. This topology is shown in the figure below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Open_Shortest_Path_First_-_OSPF/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Open_Shortest_Path_First_-_OSPF/</guid>
      <description>Open Shortest Path First - OSPF OSPF maintains the view of the network topology conceptually as a directed graph. Each router represents a vertex in the graph. Each link between neighboring routers represents a unidirectional edge and each link has an associated weight (called cost) that is either automatically derived from its bandwidth or administratively assigned. Using the weighted topology graph, each router computes a shortest path tree (SPT) with itself as the root, and applies the results to build its forwarding table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Open_Shortest_Path_First_v3_-_OSPFv3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Open_Shortest_Path_First_v3_-_OSPFv3/</guid>
      <description>Open Shortest Path First v3 - OSPFv3 OSPFv3 is a revised version of OSPFv2 to support the IPv6 address family. Refer to Open Shortest Path First (OSPF) Protocol for a discussion on the basic concepts, which remain the same between the two versions.
OSPFv3 has changed the formatting in some of the packets and LSAs either as a necessity to support IPv6 or to improve the protocol behavior based on OSPFv2 experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Policy-based_Routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Policy-based_Routing/</guid>
      <description>Policy-based Routing Typical routing systems and protocols forward traffic based on the destination address in the packet, which is used to look up an entry in a routing table. However, sometimes the traffic on your network requires a more hands-on approach. You might need to forward a packet based on the source address, the packet size, or other information in the packet header.
Policy-based routing (PBR) lets you make routing decisions based on filters that change the routing behavior of specific traffic so that you can override the routing table and influence where the traffic goes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Protocol_Independent_Multicast_-_PIM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Protocol_Independent_Multicast_-_PIM/</guid>
      <description>Protocol Independent Multicast - PIM Protocol Independent Multicast (PIM) is a multicast control plane protocol that advertises multicast sources and receivers over a routed layer 3 network. Layer 3 multicast relies on PIM to advertise information about multicast capable routers, and the location of multicast senders and receivers. For this reason, multicast cannot be sent through a routed network without PIM.
PIM has two modes of operation: Sparse Mode (PIM-SM) and Dense Mode (PIM-DM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Redistribute_Neighbor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Redistribute_Neighbor/</guid>
      <description>Redistribute Neighbor Redistribute neighbor provides a mechanism for IP subnets to span racks without forcing the end hosts to run a routing protocol.
The fundamental premise behind redistribute neighbor is to announce individual host /32 routes in the routed fabric. Other hosts on the fabric can then use this new path to access the hosts in the fabric. If multiple equal-cost paths (ECMP) are available, traffic can load balance across the available paths natively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Routing/</guid>
      <description>Routing This chapter discusses routing on switches running Cumulus Linux.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Manage Static Routes  Static Multicast Routes Static Routing via ip route Apply a Route Map for Route Updates  Configure a Gateway or Default Route Supported Route Table Entries  Forwarding Table Profiles Number of Supported Route Entries, by Platform TCAM Resource Profiles for Mellanox Switches  Caveats and Errata  Don&amp;rsquo;t Delete Routes via Linux Shell Add IPv6 Default Route with src Address on eth0 Fails without Adding Delay  Related Information  Manage Static Routes You manage static routes using NCLU or the Cumulus Linux ip route command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Segment_Routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Segment_Routing/</guid>
      <description>Segment Routing Cumulus Linux supports *segment routing, *also known as source routing, which provides the ability for a source node to specify the path a packet should take (traffic engineering). In some more advanced cases, you can use segment routing to have offline multiprotocol label switching (MPLS) controllers program labels into the network for traffic engineering.
Cumulus Linux provides full label-based forwarding, relying on BGP for label exchange. However, Cumulus Linux does not provide LDP interoperability for MPLS and it does not support VRFs for tenant isolation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Virtual_Routing_and_Forwarding_-_VRF/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/Virtual_Routing_and_Forwarding_-_VRF/</guid>
      <description>Virtual Routing and Forwarding - VRF Cumulus Linux provides virtual routing and forwarding (VRF) to allow for the presence of multiple independent routing tables working simultaneously on the same router or switch. This permits multiple network paths without the need for multiple switches. Think of this feature as VLAN for layer 3, but unlike VLANs, there is no field in the IP header carrying it. Other implementations call this feature VRF-Lite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/configuring_frrouting/comparing_nclu_and_vtysh_commands/Comparing_NCLU_and_vtysh_Commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/configuring_frrouting/comparing_nclu_and_vtysh_commands/Comparing_NCLU_and_vtysh_Commands/</guid>
      <description>Comparing NCLU and vtysh Commands Using NCLU is the primary way to configure routing in Cumulus Linux. However, an alternative exists in the the vtysh modal CLI. The available commands are as follows:
The following table compares the various FRRouting commands with their Cumulus Linux NCLU counterparts.
    Action NCLU Commands FRRouting Commands    Display the routing table cumulus@switch:~$ net show route   switch# show ip route    Create a new neighbor cumulus@switch:~$ net add bgp autonomous-system 65002 cumulus@switch:~$ net add bgp neighbor 14.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/frrouting_overview/Upgrading_from_Quagga_to_FRRouting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/layer3/frrouting_overview/Upgrading_from_Quagga_to_FRRouting/</guid>
      <description>Upgrading from Quagga to FRRouting Cumulus Linux 3.4 and later releases replace Quagga with FRRouting. This section outlines the upgrade process for users currently using Quagga.
These instructions only apply to upgrading to Cumulus Linux 3.4 or later from releases earlier than 3.4. New image installations contain frr instead of quagga or quagga-compat. If you are using any automation tools to configure your network and are installing a new Cumulus Linux image, make sure your automation tools refer to FRR and not to Quagga.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/ASIC_Monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/ASIC_Monitoring/</guid>
      <description>ASIC Monitoring Cumulus Linux provides an ASIC monitoring tool that collects and distributes data about the state of the ASIC. The monitoring tool polls for data at specific intervals and takes certain actions so that you can quickly identify and respond to problems, such as:
 Microbursts that result in longer packet latency
 Packet buffer congestion that might lead to packet drops
 Network problems with a particular switch, port, or traffic class</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/FRRouting_Log_Message_Reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/FRRouting_Log_Message_Reference/</guid>
      <description>FRRouting Log Message Reference The following table lists the HIGH severity ERROR log messages generated by FRRouting. These messages appear in /var/log/frr/frr.log.
   Category Severity
 Message # Message Text Explanation Recommended Action    Babel HIGH 16777217 BABEL Memory Errors Babel has failed to allocate memory. The system is about to run out of memory.   Find the process that is causing memory shortages and remediate that process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Monitoring_Best_Practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Monitoring_Best_Practices/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring Best Practices The following monitoring processes are considered best practices for reviewing and troubleshooting potential issues with Cumulus Linux environments. In addition, several of the more common issues have been listed, with potential solutions included.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Overview  Trend Analysis Using Metrics Generate Alerts with Triggered Logging Log Formatting  Hardware System Data  CPU Idle Time Disk Usage  Process Restart  Layer 1 Protocols and Interfaces Layer 2 Protocols Layer 3 Protocols  BGP OSPF Route and Host Entries Routing Logs  Logging Protocols and Services Device Management  Device Access Logs Device Super User Command Logs   Overview This document describes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Monitoring_System_Hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Monitoring_System_Hardware/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring System Hardware You monitor system hardware in these ways, using:
 decode-syseeprom sensors smond Net-SNMP watchdog  Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Monitor Hardware Using decode-syseeprom  Command Options Related Commands  Monitor Hardware Using sensors Monitor Switch Hardware Using SNMP Monitor System Units Using smond Keep the Switch Alive Using the Hardware Watchdog Related Information  Monitor Hardware Using decode-syseeprom The decode-syseeprom command enables you to retrieve information about the switch&amp;rsquo;s EEPROM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Monitoring_Virtual_Device_Counters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Monitoring_Virtual_Device_Counters/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring Virtual Device Counters Cumulus Linux gathers statistics for VXLANs and VLANs using virtual device counters. These counters are supported on Tomahawk, Trident II+ and Trident II-based platforms only; see the Cumulus Networks HCL for a list of supported platforms.
You can retrieve the data from these counters using tools like ip -s link show, ifconfig, /proc/net/dev, or netstat -i.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Sample VXLAN Statistics Sample VLAN Statistics  For VLANs Using the VLAN-aware Bridge Mode Driver For VLANs Using the Traditional Bridge Mode Driver  Configure the Counters in switchd  Configure the Poll Interval Configure Internal VLAN Statistics Clear Statistics  Caveats and Errata  Sample VXLAN Statistics VXLAN statistics are available as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Network_Troubleshooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Network_Troubleshooting/</guid>
      <description>Network Troubleshooting Cumulus Linux contains a number of command line and analytical tools to help you troubleshoot issues with your network.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Check Reachability Using ping Print Route Trace Using traceroute Manipulate the System ARP Cache Generate Traffic Using mz Create Counter ACL Rules Configure SPAN and ERSPAN  Limitations for SPAN/ERSPAN Configure SPAN for Switch Ports Configure SPAN for Bonds Configure ERSPAN Selective Spanning Remove SPAN Rules Monitor Control Plane Traffic with tcpdump  Related Information  Check Reachability Using ping ping is used to check reachability of a host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Resource_Diagnostics_Using_cl-resource-query/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Resource_Diagnostics_Using_cl-resource-query/</guid>
      <description>Resource Diagnostics Using cl-resource-query You can use the cl-resource-query command to retrieve information about host entries, MAC entries, layer 2 and layer 3 routes, and ECMP routes that are in use. Because Cumulus Linux synchronizes routes between the kernel and the switching silicon, if the required resource pools in hardware fill up, new kernel routes can cause existing routes to move from being fully allocated to being partially allocated. To avoid this, monitor the routes in the hardware to keep them below the ASIC limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Simple_Network_Management_Protocol_SNMP_Monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Simple_Network_Management_Protocol_SNMP_Monitoring/</guid>
      <description>Simple Network Management Protocol (SNMP) Monitoring Cumulus Linux uses the open source Net-SNMP agent snmpd, version 5.7, which provides support for most of the common industry-wide MIBs, including interface counters and TCP/UDP IP stack data.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 History Introduction to Simple Network Management Protocol  SNMP Managers SNMP Agents Management Information Base (MIB)  Getting Started Configure SNMP  Configure SNMP with NCLU  Configure SNMP Manually  Start the SNMP Daemon Configure SNMP with Management VRF (used prior to Cumulus Linux 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Single_User_Mode_-_Boot_Recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Single_User_Mode_-_Boot_Recovery/</guid>
      <description>Single User Mode - Boot Recovery Use single user mode to assist in troubleshooting system boot issues or for password recovery. To enter single user mode, follow the steps below.
 Boot the switch, as soon as you see the GRUB menu. GNU GRUB version 2.02~beta2-22+deb8u1 +----------------------------------------------------------------------------+ |*Cumulus Linux GNU/Linux | | Advanced options for Cumulus Linux GNU/Linux | | ONIE | | | +----------------------------------------------------------------------------+  Use the ^ and v arrow keys to select Advanced options for Cumulus Linux GNU/Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Troubleshooting_Network_Interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Troubleshooting_Network_Interfaces/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshooting Network Interfaces The following sections describe various ways you can troubleshoot ifupdown2. Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Enable Logging for Networking Use ifquery to Validate and Debug Interface Configurations Mako Template Errors ifdown Cannot Find an Interface that Exists Remove All References to a Child Interface MTU Set on a Logical Interface Fails with Error: &amp;ldquo;Numerical result out of range&amp;rdquo; iproute2 batch Command Failures &amp;ldquo;RTNETLINK answers: Invalid argument&amp;rdquo; Error when Adding a Port to a Bridge MLAG Peerlink Interface Drops Many Packets  Enable Logging for Networking The /etc/default/networking file contains two settings for logging:  To get ifupdown2 logs when the switch boots (stored in syslog) To enable logging when you run systemctl [start|stop|reload] networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Understanding_the_cl-support_Output_File/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/Understanding_the_cl-support_Output_File/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the cl-support Output File The cl-support script generates a compressed archive file of useful information for troubleshooting. The system either creates the archive file automatically or you can create the archive file manually.
The system creates the cl-support archive file automatically for the following reasons:
 When there is a core file dump of any application (not specific to Cumulus Linux, but something all Linux distributions support), located in /var/support/core</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/monitoring_system_hardware/network_switch_port_led_and_stats_led/Network_Switch_Port_LED_and_Status_LED_Guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/monitoring_system_hardware/network_switch_port_led_and_stats_led/Network_Switch_Port_LED_and_Status_LED_Guidelines/</guid>
      <description>Network Switch Port LED and Status LED Guidelines Data centers today have a large number of network switches manufactured by different hardware vendors running NOSes (network operating system) from different providers. This chapter provides a set of guidelines for how network port and status LEDs should appear on the front panel of a network switch. This provides a network operator with a standard way to identify the state of a switch and its ports by looking at its front panel, irrespective of the hardware vendor or NOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/network_troubleshooting/monitoring_system_statistics/Monitoring_System_Statistics_and_Network_Traffic_with_sFlow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/network_troubleshooting/monitoring_system_statistics/Monitoring_System_Statistics_and_Network_Traffic_with_sFlow/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring System Statistics and Network Traffic with sFlow sFlow is a monitoring protocol that samples network packets, application operations, and system counters. sFlow collects both interface counters and sampled 5-tuple packet information, enabling you to monitor your network traffic as well as your switch state and performance metrics. An outside server, known as an sFlow collector, is required to collect and analyze this data.
hsflowd is the daemon that samples and sends sFlow data to configured collectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/network_troubleshooting/using_nclu_to_troubleshoot/Using_NCLU_to_Troubleshoot_Your_Network_Configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/network_troubleshooting/using_nclu_to_troubleshoot/Using_NCLU_to_Troubleshoot_Your_Network_Configuration/</guid>
      <description>Using NCLU to Troubleshoot Your Network Configuration The network command line utility (NCLU) can quickly return a lot of information about your network configuration. Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 net show Commands Show Interfaces Troubleshooting Example: OpenStack Other Useful Features Install netshow on a Linux Server  net show Commands Running net show and pressing TAB displays all available command line arguments usable by net. The output looks like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/simple_network_management/using_nutanix_prisim_as_monitoring_tool/Using_Nutanix_Prism_as_a_Monitoring_Tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/simple_network_management/using_nutanix_prisim_as_monitoring_tool/Using_Nutanix_Prism_as_a_Monitoring_Tool/</guid>
      <description>Using Nutanix Prism as a Monitoring Tool Nutanix Prism is a graphical user interface (GUI) for managing infrastructure and virtual environments. In order to use it, you need to take special steps within Cumulus Linux before you can configure Prism.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Configure Cumulus Linux Configure Nutanix  Switch Information Displayed on Nutanix Prism Troubleshooting Enable LLDP/CDP on VMware ESXi (Hypervisor on Nutanix) Troubleshoot Connections without LLDP or CDP  Configure Cumulus Linux  SSH to the Cumulus Linux switch that needs to be configured, replacing [switch] below as appropriate:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/switchd_Log_Message_Reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/switchd_Log_Message_Reference/</guid>
      <description>switchd Log Message Reference The following table lists the log messages generated by switchd, organized by severity, then message text. These messages appear in /var/log/switchd.log.
    Severity Message Text Explanation Recommended Action    CRITICAL _port_group_config_values_get: hal_list_get failed on [str] List create failed. File a ticket with Cumulus Support.  CRITICAL _range_limits_get: start linux interface name buffer is NULL Invalid parameter. File a ticket with Cumulus Support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/troubleshooting_network_interfaces/monitoring_interfaces_and_transcievers_using_ethtool/Monitoring_Interfaces_and_Transceivers_Using_ethtool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/troubleshooting_network_interfaces/monitoring_interfaces_and_transcievers_using_ethtool/Monitoring_Interfaces_and_Transceivers_Using_ethtool/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring Interfaces and Transceivers Using ethtool The ethtool command enables you to query or control the network driver and hardware settings. It takes the device name (like swp1) as an argument. When the device name is the only argument to ethtool, it prints the current settings of the network device. See man ethtool(8) for details. Not all options are currently supported on switch port interfaces.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/understanding_cl-support_output_file/troubleshooting_log_files/Troubleshooting_Log_Files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/understanding_cl-support_output_file/troubleshooting_log_files/Troubleshooting_Log_Files/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshooting Log Files The only real unique entity for logging on Cumulus Linux compared to any other Linux distribution is switchd.log, which logs the HAL (hardware abstraction layer) from hardware like the Broadcom or Mellanox ASIC.
This guide on NixCraft is amazing for understanding how /var/log works. The green highlighted rows below are the most important logs and usually looked at first when debugging.
    Log Description Why is this important?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/understanding_cl-support_output_file/troubleshooting_the_etc_directory/Troubleshooting_the_etc_Directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/monitoring-troubleshooting/understanding_cl-support_output_file/troubleshooting_the_etc_directory/Troubleshooting_the_etc_Directory/</guid>
      <description>Troubleshooting the etc Directory The cl-support script replicates the /etc directory.
Files that cl-support deliberately excludes are:
    File Description    /etc/nologin nologin prevents unprivileged users from logging into the system.
  /etc/alternatives update-alternatives creates, removes, maintains and displays information about the symbolic links comprising the Debian alternatives system.
    This is the alphabetical of the output from running ls -l on the /etc directory structure created by cl-support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/Anycast_Design_Guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/Anycast_Design_Guide/</guid>
      <description>Anycast Design Guide Cumulus Networks&amp;rsquo; Routing on the Host provides the ability to run OSPF or BGP directly on server hosts. This can enable a network architecture known as anycast, where many servers can provide the same service without needing layer 2 extensions or load balancer appliances.
Anycast is not a new protocol or protocol implementation and does not require any additional network configuration. Anycast leverages the equal cost multipath (ECMP) capabilities inherent in layer 3 networks to provide stateless load sharing services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/Cumulus_Hyperconverged_Solution_with_Nutanix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/Cumulus_Hyperconverged_Solution_with_Nutanix/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus Hyperconverged Solution with Nutanix The Cumulus Hyperconverged Solution (HCS) in Cumulus Linux supports automated integration with the Nutanix Prism Management solution and the Nutanix AHV hypervisor. Cumulus HCS automatically configures ports attached to Nutanix nodes, provisions networking and manages VLANs with Nutanix Prism and Nutanix AHV.
In addition, you can augment the deployment with:
 Cumulus on a Stick for zero touch provisioning Nutanix and Cumulus HCS without any user interaction or additional equipment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/Cumulus_Networks_Services_Demos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/Cumulus_Networks_Services_Demos/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus Networks Services Demos The Cumulus Networks Services team demos provide a virtual environment built using either VirtualBox or libvirt using Vagrant to manage the VMs. This environment utilizes the reference topology shown below. Vagrant and Cumulus VX can be used together to build virtual simulations of production networks to validate configurations, develop automation code and simulate failure scenarios.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Reference Topology  IP and MAC Addressing Build the Topology  Virtual Appliance Hardware  Demos   Reference Topology The Cumulus Networks reference topology includes cabling (in DOT format for dual use with PTM), MAC addressing, IP addressing, switches and servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/Data_Center_Host_to_ToR_Architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/Data_Center_Host_to_ToR_Architecture/</guid>
      <description>Data Center Host to ToR Architecture This chapter discusses the various architectures and strategies available from the top of rack (ToR) switches all the way down to the server hosts.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Layer 2 - Architecture  Traditional Spanning Tree - Single Attached MLAG  Layer 3 Architecture  Single-attached Hosts Redistribute Neighbor Routing on the Host Routing on the VM Virtual Router Anycast with Manual Redistribution  Network Virtualization  Layer 2 - Architecture Traditional Spanning Tree - Single Attached {height=&amp;ldquo;250&amp;rdquo;}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/Docker_on_Cumulus_Linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/Docker_on_Cumulus_Linux/</guid>
      <description>Docker on Cumulus Linux Cumulus Linux 3.4 is based on Linux kernel 4.1, which supports the Docker engine. Docker can be installed directly on a Cumulus Linux switch, and Docker containers can be run natively on the switch. This section covers the installation and set up instructions for Docker.
Set up Docker on Cumulus Linux Configure the Repositories  Add the following line to the end of /etc/apt/sources.list.d/jessie.list in a text editor, and save the file:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/OpenStack_Neutron_ML2_and_Cumulus_Linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/OpenStack_Neutron_ML2_and_Cumulus_Linux/</guid>
      <description>OpenStack Neutron ML2 and Cumulus Linux The Modular Layer 2 (ML2) plugin is a framework that allows OpenStack Networking to utilize a variety of non-vendor-specific layer 2 networking technologies. The ML2 framework simplifies adding support for new layer 2 networking technologies, requiring much less initial and ongoing effort — specifically, it enables dynamic provisioning of VLAN/VXLAN on switches in OpenStack environment instead of manually provisioning L2 connectivity for each VM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/RDMA_over_Converged_Ethernet_-_RoCE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-solutions/RDMA_over_Converged_Ethernet_-_RoCE/</guid>
      <description>RDMA over Converged Ethernet - RoCE *RDMA over Converged Ethernet* (RoCE) provides the ability to write to compute or storage elements using remote direct memory access (RDMA) over an Ethernet network instead of using host CPUs. RoCE relies on congestion control and lossless Ethernet to operate. Cumulus Linux supports features that can enable lossless Ethernet for RoCE environments. Note that while Cumulus Linux can support RoCE environments, the hosts send and receive the RoCE packets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/Eng_Update_of_VXLAN_Hyperloop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/Eng_Update_of_VXLAN_Hyperloop/</guid>
      <description>Eng Update of VXLAN Hyperloop This chapter describes how to configure VXLAN gateways using a loopback cable (called a hyperloop) on non-RIOT (VXLAN routing) capable ASICs running Cumulus Linux. The Broadcom Trident II and Tomahawk ASICs have a limitation where a layer 2 bridge that contains a VXLAN interface cannot also have an IP address assigned to it. This is an expected limitation with this ASIC because of the ordering of the decapsulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/Ethernet_Virtual_Private_Network_-_EVPN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/Ethernet_Virtual_Private_Network_-_EVPN/</guid>
      <description>Ethernet Virtual Private Network - EVPN VXLAN is the de facto technology for implementing network virtualization in the data center, enabling layer 2 segments to be extended over an IP core (the underlay). The initial definition of VXLAN (RFC 7348) did not include any control plane and relied on a flood-and-learn approach for MAC address learning. An alternate deployment model was to use a controller or a technology such as Lightweight Network Virtualization (LNV) in Cumulus Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/Hybrid_Cloud_Connectivity_with_QinQ_and_VXLANs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/Hybrid_Cloud_Connectivity_with_QinQ_and_VXLANs/</guid>
      <description>Hybrid Cloud Connectivity with QinQ and VXLANs QinQ is an amendment to the IEEE 802.1Q specification that provides the capability for multiple VLAN tags to be inserted into a single Ethernet frame. The primary use case for QinQ with VXLAN is where a service provider who offers multi-tenant layer 2 connectivity between different customers’ data centers (private clouds) may also need to connect those data centers to public cloud providers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/LNV_Full_Example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/LNV_Full_Example/</guid>
      <description>LNV Full Example Lightweight Network Virtualization (LNV) is a technique for deploying VXLANs without a central controller on bare metal switches. This a full example complete with diagram. Refer to the Lightweight Network Virtualization chapter for more detailed information. This full example uses the recommended way of deploying LNV, which is to use anycast to load balance the service nodes.
LNV is a lightweight controller option. Contact Cumulus Networks with your scale requirements so we can make sure this is the right fit for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/Lightweight_Network_Virtualization_Overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/Lightweight_Network_Virtualization_Overview/</guid>
      <description>Lightweight Network Virtualization Overview Lightweight Network Virtualization (LNV) is a technique for deploying VXLANs without a central controller on bare metal switches. This solution requires no external controller or software suite; it runs the VXLAN service and registration daemons on Cumulus Linux itself. The data path between bridge entities is established on top of a layer 3 fabric by means of a simple service node coupled with traditional MAC address learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/Static_VXLAN_Configurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/Static_VXLAN_Configurations/</guid>
      <description> Static VXLAN Configurations  Static VXLAN Tunnels Static MAC Bindings with VXLAN  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/VXLAN_Routing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/VXLAN_Routing/</guid>
      <description>VXLAN Routing VXLAN routing, sometimes referred to as inter-VXLAN routing, provides IP routing between VXLAN VNIs in overlay networks. The routing of traffic is based on the inner header or the overlay tenant IP address.
Because VXLAN routing is fundamentally routing, it is most commonly deployed with a control plane, such as Ethernet Virtual Private Network (EVPN). You can set up static routing too, either with or without the Cumulus Lightweight Network Virtualization (LNV) for MAC distribution and BUM handling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/VXLAN_Scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/VXLAN_Scale/</guid>
      <description>VXLAN Scale On Broadcom Trident II and Tomahawk switches running Cumulus Linux, there is a limit to the number of VXLANs you can configure simultaneously. The limit most often given is 2000 VXLANs, but you might want to get more specific and know exactly the limit for your specific design.
While this limitation does apply to Trident II+, Trident3, or Maverick ASICs, Cumulus Linux supports the same number of VXLANs on these ASICs as it does for Trident II or Tomahawk ASICs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/VXLAN_Tunnel_DSCP_Operations__DRAFT/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/VXLAN_Tunnel_DSCP_Operations__DRAFT/</guid>
      <description>VXLAN Tunnel DSCP Operations — DRAFT The following configuration options control DSCP operations during VXLAN encapsulation and decapsulation. These operations work for applications that require end-to-end quality of service, such as RDMA over Converged Ethernet.
On Mellanox switches, you can use these options to propagate explicit congestion notification (ECN) between the underlay and overlay. Because they are based on RFC-6040, which describes how to construct the IP header of an ECN field on both ingress to and egress from an IP-in-IP tunnel, this feature is always enabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/Virtualization_Integrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/Virtualization_Integrations/</guid>
      <description> Virtualization Integrations Cumulus Linux integrates with a number of VXLAN controller-based virtualization solutions.
 Integrating Hardware VTEPs with Midokura MidoNet and OpenStack Integrating Hardware VTEPs with VMware NSX-V Integrating Hardware VTEPs with VMware NSX-MH OVSDB Server High Availability  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/static_vxlan_configurations/static_mac_bindings/Static_MAC_Bindings_with_VXLAN/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/static_vxlan_configurations/static_mac_bindings/Static_MAC_Bindings_with_VXLAN/</guid>
      <description>Static MAC Bindings with VXLAN Cumulus Linux includes native Linux VXLAN kernel support.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Requirements Example VXLAN Configuration Configure the Static MAC Bindings VXLAN Troubleshooting  Requirements A VXLAN configuration requires a Broadcom switch with the Tomahawk, Trident II+, or Trident II ASIC running Cumulus Linux 2.0 or later, or a Mellanox switch with the Spectrum ASIC running Cumulus Linux 3.2.0 or later.
For a basic VXLAN configuration, make sure that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/static_vxlan_configurations/static_vxlan_tunnels/Static_VXLAN_Tunnels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/static_vxlan_configurations/static_vxlan_tunnels/Static_VXLAN_Tunnels/</guid>
      <description>Static VXLAN Tunnels In VXLAN-based networks, there are a range of complexities and challenges in determining the destination *virtual tunnel endpoints* (VTEPs) for any given VXLAN. At scale, various solutions, including Lightweight Network Virtualization (LNV), controller-based options like Midokura MidoNet or VMware NSX and even new standards like EVPN are attempts to address these complexities, however do retain their own complexities.
Enter static VXLAN tunnels, which simply serve to connect two VTEPs in a given environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/virtualization_integrations/integrating_hardware_vteps_vmware_nsx-mh/Integrating_Hardware_VTEPs_with_VMware_NSX-MH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/virtualization_integrations/integrating_hardware_vteps_vmware_nsx-mh/Integrating_Hardware_VTEPs_with_VMware_NSX-MH/</guid>
      <description>Integrating Hardware VTEPs with VMware NSX-MH Switches running Cumulus Linux can integrate with VMware NSX Multi-Hypervisor (MH) to act as hardware VTEP gateways. The VMware NSX-MH controller provides consistent provisioning across virtual and physical server infrastructures.
{width=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;}
Cumulus Linux also supports integration with VMware NSX in high availability mode. Refer to OVSDB Server High Availability.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Getting Started Configure the Switch for NSX-MH Integration  Start the openvswitch-vtep Service Configure the NSX-MH Integration Using the Configuration Script Configure the NSX-MH Integration Manually  Provision VMware NSX-V  Configure the Switch as a VTEP Gateway  Configure the Transport and Logical Layers  Configure the Transport Layer Configure the Logical Layer Define Logical Switch Ports  Verify the VXLAN Configuration  Getting Started Before you integrate VXLANs with NSX-MH, make sure you have a layer 2 gateway; a Broadcom Tomahawk, Trident II+, Trident II, Maverick, or Mellanox Spectrum switch running Cumulus Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/virtualization_integrations/integrating_vteps_midonet_openstack/Integrating_Hardware_VTEPs_with_Midokura_MidoNet_and_OpenStack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/virtualization_integrations/integrating_vteps_midonet_openstack/Integrating_Hardware_VTEPs_with_Midokura_MidoNet_and_OpenStack/</guid>
      <description>Integrating Hardware VTEPs with Midokura MidoNet and OpenStack Cumulus Linux seamlessly integrates with the MidoNet OpenStack infrastructure, where the switches provide the VTEP gateway for terminating VXLAN tunnels from within MidoNet. MidoNet connects to the OVSDB server running on the Cumulus Linux switch, and exchanges information about the VTEPs and MAC addresses associated with the OpenStack Neutron networks. This provides seamless Ethernet connectivity between virtual and physical server infrastructures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/virtualization_integrations/integrating_vteps_vmware_nsx-v/Integrating_Hardware_VTEPs_with_VMware_NSX-V/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/virtualization_integrations/integrating_vteps_vmware_nsx-v/Integrating_Hardware_VTEPs_with_VMware_NSX-V/</guid>
      <description>Integrating Hardware VTEPs with VMware NSX-V Switches running Cumulus Linux can integrate with VMware NSX-V to act as hardware VTEP gateways. The VMware NSX-V controller provides consistent provisioning across virtual and physical server infrastructures.
{width=&amp;ldquo;500&amp;rdquo;}
Cumulus Linux also supports integration with VMware NSX in high availability mode. Refer to OVSDB Server High Availability.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Getting Started Configure the Switch for NSX-V Integration  Start the openvswitch-vtep Service Configure the NSX-V Integration Using the Configuration Script Configure the NSX-V Integration Manually  Provision VMware NSX-V  Configure the Switch as a VTEP Gateway  Configure the Transport and Logical Layers  Configure the Transport Layer Configure the Logical Layer Define Logical Switch Ports  Verify the VXLAN Configuration  Getting Started Before you integrate VXLANs with NSX-V, make sure you have a layer 2 gateway; a Broadcom Tomahawk, Trident II+, Trident II, Maverick or Mellanox Spectrum switch running Cumulus Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/virtualization_integrations/ovsdb_server_high_availability/OVSDB_Server_High_Availability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/network-visualization/virtualization_integrations/ovsdb_server_high_availability/OVSDB_Server_High_Availability/</guid>
      <description>OVSDB Server High Availability Early Access Feature
OVSDB server high availability is an early access feature in Cumulus Linux 3.7.
Cumulus Linux supports integration with VMware NSX in both standalone mode and OVSDB server high availability mode (where the data plane is running in active-active mode). For information about VMware NSX in standalone mode and for a description of the components that work together to integrate VMware NSX and Cumulus Linux, see Integrating Hardware VTEPs with VMware NSX-MH or Integrating Hardware VTEPs with VMware NSX-V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/quick-start/Quick_Start_Guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/quick-start/Quick_Start_Guide/</guid>
      <description>Quick Start Guide This quick start guide provides an end-to-end setup process for installing and running Cumulus Linux, as well as a collection of example commands for getting started after installation is complete.
Prerequisites
Intermediate-level Linux knowledge is assumed for this guide. You should be familiar with basic text editing, Unix file permissions, and process monitoring. A variety of text editors are pre-installed, including vi and nano.
You must have access to a Linux or UNIX shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Authentication_Authorization_and_Accounting/</guid>
      <description> Authentication, Authorization and Accounting  SSH for Remote Access User Accounts Using sudo to Delegate Privileges LDAP Authentication and Authorization TACACS Plus RADIUS AAA  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Configuring_a_Global_Proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Configuring_a_Global_Proxy/</guid>
      <description>Configuring a Global Proxy You configure global HTTP and HTTPS proxies in the /etc/profile.d/ directory of Cumulus Linux. To do so, set the http_proxy and https_proxy variables, which tells the switch the address of the proxy server to use to fetch URLs on the command line. This is useful for programs such as apt/apt-get, curl and wget, which can all use this proxy.
 In a terminal, create a new file in the /etc/profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Configuring_switchd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Configuring_switchd/</guid>
      <description>Configuring switchd switchd is the daemon at the heart of Cumulus Linux. It communicates between the switch and Cumulus Linux, and all the applications running on Cumulus Linux. 
The switchd configuration is stored in /etc/cumulus/switchd.conf.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 The switchd File System Configure switchd Parameters Restart switchd  The switchd File System switchd also exports a file system, mounted on /cumulus/switchd, that presents all the switchd configuration options as a series of files arranged in a tree structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Copy_of_Netfilter_-_ACLs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Copy_of_Netfilter_-_ACLs/</guid>
      <description>Copy of Netfilter - ACLs Netfilter is the packet filtering framework in Cumulus Linux as well as most other Linux distributions. There are a number of tools available for configuring ACLs in Cumulus Linux, including:
 iptables, ip6tables and ebtables are Linux userspace tools to administer filtering rules for IPv4 packets, IPv6 packets and Ethernet frames (layer 2 using MAC addresses) respectively.  NCLU, a Cumulus Linux-specific userspace tool for configuring custom ACLs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/HTTP_API/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/HTTP_API/</guid>
      <description>HTTP API Cumulus Linux implements an HTTP application programing interface to OpenStack ML2 driver and NCLU. Rather than accessing Cumulus Linux using SSH, you can interact with the switch using an HTTP client, such as cURL, HTTPie or a web browser.
The HTTP API service is enabled by default on chassis hardware only. However, the associated server is configured to only listen to traffic originating from within the chassis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Netfilter_-_ACLs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Netfilter_-_ACLs/</guid>
      <description>Netfilter - ACLs Netfilter is the packet filtering framework in Cumulus Linux as well as most other Linux distributions. There are a number of tools available for configuring ACLs in Cumulus Linux:
 iptables, ip6tables, and ebtables are Linux userspace tools used to administer filtering rules for IPv4 packets, IPv6 packets, and Ethernet frames (layer 2 using MAC addresses).  NCLU is a Cumulus Linux-specific userspace tool used to configure custom ACLs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Network_Command_Line_Utility_-_NCLU/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Network_Command_Line_Utility_-_NCLU/</guid>
      <description>Network Command Line Utility - NCLU  The Network Command Line Utility (NCLU) is a command line interface for Cumulus Networks products that simplifies the networking configuration process for all users.
NCLU resides in the Linux user space and provides consistent access to networking commands directly through bash, making configuration and troubleshooting simple and easy; no need to edit files or enter modes and sub-modes. NCLU provides these benefits:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Power_over_Ethernet_-_PoE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Power_over_Ethernet_-_PoE/</guid>
      <description>Power over Ethernet - PoE Cumulus Linux supports Power over Ethernet (PoE) and PoE+, so certain Cumulus Linux switches can supply power from Ethernet switch ports to enabled devices over the Ethernet cables that connect them. Power over Ethernet (PoE) is capable of powering devices up to 15W, while PoE+ can power devices up to 30W.
The currently supported platform is the Edge-Core AS4610-54P, which supports PoE and PoE+ and configuration over Ethernet layer 2 LLDP for power negotiation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Services_and_Daemons_in_Cumulus_Linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Services_and_Daemons_in_Cumulus_Linux/</guid>
      <description>Services and Daemons in Cumulus Linux *Services* (also known as daemons) and *processes* are at the heart of how a Linux system functions. Most of the time a service takes care of itself; you just enable and start it, then let it run. However, because a Cumulus Linux switch is a Linux system, you have the ability to dig deeper if you like. Services may start multiple processes as they run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Setting_Date_and_Time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/Setting_Date_and_Time/</guid>
      <description>Setting Date and Time Setting the time zone, date and time requires root privileges; use sudo.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Set the Time Zone  Edit the /etc/timezone File Use the Guided Wizard  Set the Date and Time Set the Time Using NTP and NCLU Specify the NTP Source Interface NTP Default Configuration Precision Time Protocol (PTP) Boundary Clock  Enable the PTP Boundary Clock on the Switch Configure the PTP Boundary Clock Example Configuration Verify PTP Boundary Clock Configuration View PTP Status Information Delete PTP Boundary Clock Configuration  Use NTP in a DHCP Environment Related Information  Set the Time Zone You can use one of two methods to set the time zone on the switch:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/authentication_authorization_accounting/LDAP_Authentication_and_Authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/authentication_authorization_accounting/LDAP_Authentication_and_Authorization/</guid>
      <description>LDAP Authentication and Authorization Cumulus Linux uses Pluggable Authentication Modules (PAM) and Name Service Switch (NSS) for user authentication.
NSS specifies the order of information sources used to resolve names for each service. Using this with authentication and authorization, it provides the order and location used for user lookup and group mapping on the system. PAM handles the interaction between the user and the system, providing login handling, session setup, authentication of users, and authorization of user actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/authentication_authorization_accounting/RADIUS_AAA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/authentication_authorization_accounting/RADIUS_AAA/</guid>
      <description>RADIUS AAA Cumulus Networks offers add-on packages that enable RADIUS users to log in to Cumulus Linux switches in a transparent way with minimal configuration. There is no need to create accounts or directories on the switch. Authentication is handled with PAM and includes login, ssh, sudo and su.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Install the RADIUS Packages Configure the RADIUS Client Enable Login without Local Accounts Local Fallback Authentication Verify RADIUS Client Configuration Remove RADIUS Client Packages Limitations Related Information  Install the RADIUS Packages The RADIUS packages are not included in the base Cumulus Linux image; there is no RADIUS metapackage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/authentication_authorization_accounting/SSH_for_Remote_Access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/authentication_authorization_accounting/SSH_for_Remote_Access/</guid>
      <description>SSH for Remote Access You can generate authentication keys to access a Cumulus Linux switch securely with the ssh-keygen component of the Secure Shell (SSH) protocol. Cumulus Linux uses the OpenSSH package to provide this functionality. This section describes how to generate an SSH key pair.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 Generate an SSH Key Pair Related Information  Generate an SSH Key Pair  To generate the SSH key pair, run the ssh-keygen command and follow the prompts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/authentication_authorization_accounting/TACACS_Plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/authentication_authorization_accounting/TACACS_Plus/</guid>
      <description>TACACS Plus Cumulus Linux implements TACACS+ client AAA (Accounting, Authentication, and Authorization) in a transparent way with minimal configuration. The client implements the TACACS+ protocol as described in this IETF document. There is no need to create accounts or directories on the switch. Accounting records are sent to all configured TACACS+ servers by default. Use of per-command authorization requires additional setup on the switch.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/authentication_authorization_accounting/User_Accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/authentication_authorization_accounting/User_Accounts/</guid>
      <description>User Accounts By default, Cumulus Linux has two user accounts: cumulus and root.
The cumulus account:
 Uses the default password CumulusLinux! Is a user account in the sudo group with sudo privileges. Can log in to the system through all the usual channels, such as console and SSH. Along with the cumulus group, has both show and edit rights for NCLU.  The *root* account:
 Has the default password disabled by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/authentication_authorization_accounting/Using_sudo_to_Delegate_Privileges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/authentication_authorization_accounting/Using_sudo_to_Delegate_Privileges/</guid>
      <description>Using sudo to Delegate Privileges By default, Cumulus Linux has two user accounts: root and cumulus. The cumulus account is a normal user and is in the group sudo.
You can add more user accounts as needed. Like the cumulus account, these accounts must use sudo to execute privileged commands.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes &amp;hellip;
 sudo Basics sudoers Examples Related Information  sudo Basics sudo allows you to execute a command as superuser or another user as specified by the security policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/netfilter_acls/default_cumulus_linux_acl_config/Default_Cumulus_Linux_ACL_Configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/netfilter_acls/default_cumulus_linux_acl_config/Default_Cumulus_Linux_ACL_Configuration/</guid>
      <description>Default Cumulus Linux ACL Configuration The Cumulus Linux default ACL configuration is split into three parts, as outlined in the netfilter ACL documentation: IP tables, IPv6 tables, and EB tables. The sections below describe the default configurations for each part. You can see the default file by clicking the Default ACL Configuration link:
{.expand-control-image}Default ACL Configuration
cumulus@switch:~$ sudo cl-acltool -L all ------------------------------- Listing rules of type iptables: ------------------------------- TABLE filter : Chain INPUT (policy ACCEPT 167 packets, 16481 bytes) pkts bytes target prot opt in out source destination 0 0 DROP all -- swp+ any 240.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/netfilter_acls/default_cumulus_linux_acl_config/Filtering_Learned_MAC_Addresses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/Cumulus-Linux/system-config/netfilter_acls/default_cumulus_linux_acl_config/Filtering_Learned_MAC_Addresses/</guid>
      <description>Filtering Learned MAC Addresses On Broadcom switches, a MAC address is learned on a bridge regardless of whether or not a received packet is dropped by an ACL. This is due to how the hardware learns MAC addresses and occurs before the ACL lookup. This can be a security or resource problem as the MAC address table has the potential to get filled with bogus MAC addresses; a malfunctioning host, network error, loop, or malicious attack on a shared layer 2 platform can create an outage for other hosts if the same MAC address is learned on another port.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/Release_Notes/Cumulus_NetQ_2.0_Release_Notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/Release_Notes/Cumulus_NetQ_2.0_Release_Notes/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus NetQ 2.0 Release Notes Overview These release notes support Cumulus NetQ 2.0.0 and 2.0.1 releases and describe currently available features and known issues.
Stay up to Date   Subscribe to our product bulletin mailing list to receive important announcements and updates about issues that arise in our products. Subscribe to our security announcement mailing list to receive alerts whenever we update our software for security issues.   Contents  Overview Stay up to Date  What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus NetQ 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_switches/Monitor_Switches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_switches/Monitor_Switches/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Switches With the NetQ UI, you can monitor individual switches separately from the network. You are able to view the various components deployed for all switches in the network. Being able to monitor switch component inventory aids in upgrade, compliance, and other planning tasks.
For network-wide monitoring, refer to Monitor the Network.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes&amp;hellip;
 Switch Inventory Card Workflow Summary View a Summary of Communication Status for All Switches  View the Number of Types of Any Component Deployed View the Distribution of Any Component Deployed View the Number of Switches with Invalid or Missing Licenses View the Most Commonly Deployed ASIC View the Number of Switches with a Particular NetQ Agent View a List of All Data for a Specific Component  Switch Inventory Card Workflow Summary The small Switch Inventory card displays:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_the_network/monitor_alarm_events/Monitor_Alarm_Events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_the_network/monitor_alarm_events/Monitor_Alarm_Events/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Alarm Events Two event workflows, the Alarms card workflow and the Info card workflow, provide a view into the events occurring in the network. The Alarms card workflow tracks critical severity events, whereas the Info card workflow tracks all warning, info, and debug severity events.
To focus on events from a single device perspective, refer to Monitor Switches. To monitor informational alarms, refer to Monitor Informational Events.
Contents {.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_the_network/monitor_informational_events/Monitor_Informational_Events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_the_network/monitor_informational_events/Monitor_Informational_Events/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Informational Events Two event workflows, the Alarms card workflow and the Info card workflow, provide a view into the events occurring in the network. The Alarms card workflow tracks critical severity events, whereas the Info card workflow tracks all warning, info, and debug severity events.
To focus on events from a single device perspective, refer to Monitor Switches. To monitor alarms, refer to Monitor Alarm Events.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes how to&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_the_network/monitor_network_health/Monitor_Network_Health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_the_network/monitor_network_health/Monitor_Network_Health/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Network Health As with any network, one of the challenges is keeping track of all of the moving parts. With the NetQ GUI, you can view the overall health of your network at a glance and then delve deeper for periodic checks or as conditions arise that require attention. For a general understanding of how well your network is operating, the Network Health card workflow is the best place to start as it contains the highest view and performance rollups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_the_network/monitor_network_inventory/Monitor_Network_Inventory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_the_network/monitor_network_inventory/Monitor_Network_Inventory/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Network Inventory With NetQ, a network administrator can monitor both the switch hardware and its operating system for misconfigurations or misbehaving services. The Devices Inventory card workflow provides a view into the switches and hosts installed in your network and their various hardware and software components. The workflow contains a small card with a count of each device type in your network, a medium card displaying the operating systems running on each set of devices, large cards with component information statistics, and full-screen cards displaying tables with attributes of all switches and all hosts in your network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_the_network/monitor_network_protocols/Monitor_Network_Layer_Protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/monitor_the_network/monitor_network_protocols/Monitor_Network_Layer_Protocols/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Network Layer Protocols With NetQ, a network administrator can monitor OSI Layer 3 network protocols running on Linux-based hosts, including IP (Internet Protocol), BGP (Border Gateway Protocol) and OSPF (Open Shortest Path First). NetQ provides the ability to:  Validate protocol configurations Validate layer 3 communication paths  It helps answer questions such as:
 Who are the IP neighbors for a switch?
 How many IPv4 and IPv6 addresses am I using?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/netq_ui_overview/NetQ_User_Interface_Overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/netq_ui_overview/NetQ_User_Interface_Overview/</guid>
      <description>NetQ User Interface Overview The NetQ 2.0.0 graphical user interface (UI) enables you to access NetQ capabilities through a web browser as opposed to through a terminal window using the Command Line Interface (CLI). Visual representations of the health of the network, inventory, and system events make it easy to both find faults and misconfigurations and to fix them. The UI is supported on Google Chrome. Other popular browsers may be used, but have not been tested and may have some presentation issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/ui_preface/UI_Preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/UI_User_Guide/ui_preface/UI_Preface/</guid>
      <description>UI Preface A variety of resources are available for you to become familiar with Cumulus NetQ and to take advantage of its monitoring and analytic capabilities. These resources are identified here along with information about how the content is presented.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes&amp;hellip;
 What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus NetQ 2.0.0 Available Documentation Document Formatting  Typographical Conventions Note Conventions    What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus NetQ 2.0.0 Cumulus NetQ 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/CLI_Preface/CLI_Preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/CLI_Preface/CLI_Preface/</guid>
      <description>CLI Preface A variety of resources are available for you to become familiar with Cumulus NetQ and to take advantage of its monitoring and analytic capabilities. These resources are identified here along with information about how the content is presented.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes&amp;hellip;
 What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus NetQ 2.0.0 Available Documentation Document Formatting  Typographical Conventions Note Conventions    What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus NetQ 2.0.0 Cumulus NetQ 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/automate_common_tasks/Automate_Common_and_Repetitive_Tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/automate_common_tasks/Automate_Common_and_Repetitive_Tasks/</guid>
      <description>Automate Common and Repetitive Tasks NetQ commands can also be run in an automation tool, such as Ansible, Chef, or Puppet; depending on the outcome of the automation tests, the script can either continue the deployment, or roll back the changes until the issues are addressed.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes how to&amp;hellip;
 Run NetQ Commands in Automation Scripts  Run NetQ Commands in Automation Scripts Using NetQ for preventative care of your network pairs well with automation scripts and playbooks to prevent errors on your network before deploying the configuration to your production network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/command_line_overview/NetQ_Command_Line_Overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/command_line_overview/NetQ_Command_Line_Overview/</guid>
      <description>NetQ Command Line Overview The NetQ CLI provides access to all of the network state and event information collected by the NetQ Agents. It behaves the same way most CLIs behave, with groups of commands used to display related information, the ability to use TAB completion when entering commands, and to get help for given commands and options. The commands are grouped into four categories: check and show, agent and notifier, trace, and resolve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_containter_environments/Monitor_Container_Environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_containter_environments/Monitor_Container_Environments/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Container Environments The NetQ Agent monitors container environments the same way it monitors physical servers. There is no special implementation. The NetQ Agent pulls data from the container as it would pull data from a Cumulus Linux switch or Linux host. It can be installed on a Linux server or in a Linux VM. NetQ Agent integrates with container orchestrators including Kubernetes and Docker Swarm.
NetQ monitors many aspects of containers on your network, including their:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_data_link_layer/Monitor_Data_Link_Layer_Devices_and_Protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_data_link_layer/Monitor_Data_Link_Layer_Devices_and_Protocols/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Data Link Layer Devices and Protocols With NetQ, a network administrator can monitor OSI Layer 2 devices and protocols, including switches, bridges, link control, and physical media access. Keeping track of the various data link layer devices in your network ensures consistent and error-free communications between devices. NetQ provides the ability to:  Monitor and validate device and protocol configurations View available communication paths between devices  It helps answer questions such as:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_linux_hosts/Monitor_Linux_Hosts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_linux_hosts/Monitor_Linux_Hosts/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Linux Hosts Running NetQ on Linux hosts provides unprecedented network visibility, giving the network operator a complete view of the entire infastrucutre’s network connectivity instead of just from the network devices.
The NetQ Agent is supported on the following Linux hosts:
 CentOS 7 Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7.1 Ubuntu 16.04  You need to install the OS-specific NetQ metapack on every host you want to monitor with NetQ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_network_health/Monitor_Overall_Network_Health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_network_health/Monitor_Overall_Network_Health/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Overall Network Health NetQ provides the information you need to monitor the health of your network fabric, devices, and interfaces. You are able to easily validate the operation and view the configuration across the entire network from switches to hosts to containers. For example, you can monitor the operation of routing protocols and virtual network configurations, the status of NetQ Agents and hardware components, and the operation and efficiency of interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_network_layer/Monitor_Network_Protocols_and_Services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_network_layer/Monitor_Network_Protocols_and_Services/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Network Protocols and Services The Network Services card workflows provide a network-wide view into the routing, link, and virtual network protocols installed in your network. In this release, you can monitor the network-wide behavior or a single session of the BGP, EVPN, MLAG, and LLDP services. Each protocol has its own card workflow containing:
 a small card with an overall status,  a medium card displaying key attributes of the protocol,  a large card with detailed performance statistics, some with additional tabs, and  full screen cards displaying attributes of all associated switches, sessions, alarms or other relevant data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_physical_layer/Monitor_Physical_Layer_Components/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_physical_layer/Monitor_Physical_Layer_Components/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Physical Layer Components With NetQ, a network administrator can monitor OSI Layer 1 physical components on network devices, including interfaces, ports, links, and peers. NetQ provides the ability to:  Manage physical inventory: view the performance and status of various components of a switch or host server Validate configurations: verify the configuration of network peers and ports  It helps answer questions such as:
 Are any individual or bonded links down?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_switch_hardware/Monitor_Switch_Hardware_and_Software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_switch_hardware/Monitor_Switch_Hardware_and_Software/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Switch Hardware and Software With NetQ, a network administrator can monitor both the switch hardware and software components for misconfigurations. NetQ helps answer questions such as:
 What switches do I have in the network?
 Are all switches licensed correctly?
 Do all switches have NetQ agents running?
  NetQ uses LLDP (Link Layer Discovery Protocol) to collect port information. NetQ can also identify peer ports connected to DACs (Direct Attached Cables) and AOCs (Active Optical Cables) without using LLDP, even if the link is not UP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_virtual_overlays/Monitor_Virtual_Network_Overlays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/monitor_virtual_overlays/Monitor_Virtual_Network_Overlays/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Virtual Network Overlays With NetQ, a network administrator can monitor virtual network components in the data center, including VXLAN, EVPN, and LNV software constructs. NetQ provides the ability to:  Manage virtual constructs: view the performance and status of VXLANs, EVPN, and LNV Validate overlay communication paths  It helps answer questions such as:
 Is my overlay configured and operating correctly?
 Is my control plane configured correctly?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/resolve_issues/Resolve_Issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/resolve_issues/Resolve_Issues/</guid>
      <description>Resolve Issues Monitoring of systems inevitably leads to the need to troubleshoot and resolve the issues found. In fact network management follows a common pattern as shown in this diagram.
{width=&amp;ldquo;700&amp;rdquo;}
This topic describes some of the tools and commands you can use to troubleshoot issues with the network and NetQ itself.  Methods for Diagnosing Network Issues Resolve MLAG Issues Investigate NetQ Issues   Attachments: {width=&amp;ldquo;8&amp;rdquo; height=&amp;ldquo;8&amp;rdquo;} image2018-10-2 11:29:59.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/resolve_issues/Resolve_MLAG_Issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/resolve_issues/Resolve_MLAG_Issues/</guid>
      <description>Resolve MLAG Issues This topic outlines a few scenarios that illustrate how you use NetQ to troubleshoot MLAG on Cumulus Linux switches. Each starts with a log message that indicates the current MLAG state.
NetQ can monitor many aspects of an MLAG configuration, including:
 Verifying the current state of all nodes Verifying the dual connectivity state Checking that the peer link is part of the bridge Verifying whether MLAG bonds are not bridge members Verifying whether the VXLAN interface is not a bridge member Checking for remote-side service failures caused by systemctl Checking for VLAN-VNI mapping mismatches Checking for layer 3 MTU mismatches on peerlink subinterfaces Checking for VXLAN active-active address inconsistencies Verifying that STP priorities are the same across both peers  Contents {.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/resolve_issues/investiage_netq_issues/Investigate_NetQ_Issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/resolve_issues/investiage_netq_issues/Investigate_NetQ_Issues/</guid>
      <description>Investigate NetQ Issues There are several paths you can take to locate and investigate issues that occur in the NetQ software itself, including viewing configuration and log files, verifying NetQ Agent health, and verifying NetQ Platform configuration. If these do not produce a resolution, you can capture a log to use in discussion with Cumulus Networks support team.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes how to&amp;hellip;
 Browse Configuration and Log Files Check NetQ Agent Health Generate a Support File  Browse Configuration and Log Files To aid in troubleshooting issues with NetQ, there are the following configuration and log files that can provide insight into the root cause of the issue:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/resolve_issues/methods_for_diagnosing_issues/Methods_for_Diagnosing_Network_Issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/cli_user_guide/resolve_issues/methods_for_diagnosing_issues/Methods_for_Diagnosing_Network_Issues/</guid>
      <description>Methods for Diagnosing Network Issues NetQ provides users with the ability to go back in time to replay the network state, see fabric-wide event change logs and root cause state deviations. The NetQ Telemetry Server maintains data collected by NetQ agents in a time-series database, making fabric-wide events available for analysis. This enables you to replay and analyze network-wide events for better visibility and to correlate patterns. This allows for root-cause analysis and optimization of network configs for the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/config_optional_netq/Configuring_Optional_NetQ_Capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/config_optional_netq/Configuring_Optional_NetQ_Capabilities/</guid>
      <description>Configuring Optional NetQ Capabilities After you have installed NetQ applications package and the NetQ Agents, you may want to configure some of the additional capabilities that NetQ offers. This topic describes how to install, setup, and configure these capabilities.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes how to&amp;hellip;
 Integrate NetQ with an Event Notification Application  NetQ Notifier  Event Message Format  NetQ Notification Commands Overview Configure NetQ Event Logging Configure PagerDuty Using NetQ CLI Configure Slack Using NetQ CLI View Integrations  Create NetQ Notifier Filters  Build Filter Rules  Example: Create a Filter for Events from a Selected Switch Example: Create a Filter to Drop Notifications from a Given Interface Example: Add Multiple Rules to a Filter Example: Create a Filter to Send BGP Session State Notifications to Slack Example: Create a Filter to Drop All Temperature-Related Event Notifications Example: Create a Filter for License Validation Event Notifications  Integrate with a Hardware Chassis  Integrate NetQ with an Event Notification Application By default, alert messages are sent to the database; however, other third-party tools may be configured to receive the alert messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/deployment_preface/Deployment_Preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/deployment_preface/Deployment_Preface/</guid>
      <description>Deployment Preface A variety of resources are available for you to become familiar with Cumulus NetQ and aid in its deployment. These are identified here along with information about how the content is presented.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes&amp;hellip;
 What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus NetQ 2.0.0 Available Documentation Document Formatting  Typographical Conventions Note Conventions    What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus NetQ 2.0.0 Cumulus NetQ 2.0.0 includes the following new and updated features:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/install_netq/Install_NetQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/install_netq/Install_NetQ/</guid>
      <description>Install NetQ If you have purchased a NetQ Appliance, the only installation steps required are to load the NetQ Agent on any host you want to monitor. If you already have a Cumulus Linux switch and you want to add NetQ functionality to it, installation involves verifying your server meets the hardware and software requirements, loading the software onto the switch, and then loading the agent on the hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/maintain_netq/Maintain_NetQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/maintain_netq/Maintain_NetQ/</guid>
      <description>Maintain NetQ While regular maintenance of NetQ is not required, there are some tasks that you may want to perform in the course of everyday operations. As the network changes, you might have the need to add or remove monitored nodes, notification integrations, and NetQ Agents for example. You might also need to restore NetQ to a prior version or upgrade to a new version. Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes how to&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/netq_primer/Cumulus_NetQ_Primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/netq_primer/Cumulus_NetQ_Primer/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus NetQ Primer Cumulus® NetQ is a network operations tool set that provides actionable insight into and operational intelligence about the health of the entire Linux-based data center — from the container, virtual machine, or host, all the way to the switch and port. Working hand-in-hand with Cumulus Linux, NetQ enables organizations to validate network state, both during regular operations and for post-mortem diagnostic analysis. Running on Cumulus Linux switches and other certified systems — such as Ubuntu®, Red Hat®, and CentOS hosts — NetQ captures network data and other state information in real time, providing cloud architects and network operations teams the ability to operate with visibility into the entire network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/getting_started/Getting_Started_with_the_Cumulus_NetQ_Appliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/getting_started/Getting_Started_with_the_Cumulus_NetQ_Appliance/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started with the Cumulus NetQ Appliance The Cumulus NetQ appliance provides a complete monitoring solution for your network; the server comes preloaded with a Cumulus Linux image that includes Cumulus NetQ services, a Cumulus Linux license and certified cables and optics.
This guide helps you get your Cumulus NetQ appliance up and running in a few minutes.
Contents  What&amp;rsquo;s in the Box? Installing and Configuring the Appliance  Configuring the Password, Hostname and IP Address Reviewing and Committing Your Changes Backing Up Your Appliance Default Configuration  Learning More Getting Support  What&amp;rsquo;s in the Box?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/software_installation_guide/Cumulus_NetQ_Appliance_Software_Installation_Guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/software_installation_guide/Cumulus_NetQ_Appliance_Software_Installation_Guide/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus NetQ Appliance Software Installation Guide Introduction This guide illustrates how to install ONIE and Cumulus Linux onto the Cumulus NetQ appliance. You need two USB drives with at least 1GB of storage each. Install ONIE Obtain the ONIE Installation Image Obtain an ONIE installation .ISO image from Cumulus Networks. The file should be named something like this:
onie-recovery-x86_64-cumulus_x86_64-r0.iso Copy the ONIE .ISO Image to a USB Drive Use the Win32 Disk Imager program to copy the .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>