<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cumulus Networks Documentation</title>
    <link>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cumulus Networks Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/config_optional_netq/Configuring_Optional_NetQ_Capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/config_optional_netq/Configuring_Optional_NetQ_Capabilities/</guid>
      <description>Configuring Optional NetQ Capabilities After you have installed NetQ applications package and the NetQ Agents, you may want to configure some of the additional capabilities that NetQ offers. This topic describes how to install, setup, and configure these capabilities.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes how to&amp;hellip;
 Integrate NetQ with an Event Notification Application  NetQ Notifier  Event Message Format  NetQ Notification Commands Overview Configure NetQ Event Logging Configure PagerDuty Using NetQ CLI Configure Slack Using NetQ CLI View Integrations  Create NetQ Notifier Filters  Build Filter Rules  Example: Create a Filter for Events from a Selected Switch Example: Create a Filter to Drop Notifications from a Given Interface Example: Add Multiple Rules to a Filter Example: Create a Filter to Send BGP Session State Notifications to Slack Example: Create a Filter to Drop All Temperature-Related Event Notifications Example: Create a Filter for License Validation Event Notifications  Integrate with a Hardware Chassis  Integrate NetQ with an Event Notification Application By default, alert messages are sent to the database; however, other third-party tools may be configured to receive the alert messages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/deployment_preface/Deployment_Preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/deployment_preface/Deployment_Preface/</guid>
      <description>Deployment Preface A variety of resources are available for you to become familiar with Cumulus NetQ and aid in its deployment. These are identified here along with information about how the content is presented.
Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes&amp;hellip;
 What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus NetQ 2.0.0 Available Documentation Document Formatting  Typographical Conventions Note Conventions    What&amp;rsquo;s New in Cumulus NetQ 2.0.0 Cumulus NetQ 2.0.0 includes the following new and updated features:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/install_netq/Install_NetQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/install_netq/Install_NetQ/</guid>
      <description>Install NetQ If you have purchased a NetQ Appliance, the only installation steps required are to load the NetQ Agent on any host you want to monitor. If you already have a Cumulus Linux switch and you want to add NetQ functionality to it, installation involves verifying your server meets the hardware and software requirements, loading the software onto the switch, and then loading the agent on the hosts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/maintain_netq/Maintain_NetQ/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/maintain_netq/Maintain_NetQ/</guid>
      <description>Maintain NetQ While regular maintenance of NetQ is not required, there are some tasks that you may want to perform in the course of everyday operations. As the network changes, you might have the need to add or remove monitored nodes, notification integrations, and NetQ Agents for example. You might also need to restore NetQ to a prior version or upgrade to a new version. Contents {.expand-control-image}This topic describes how to&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/netq_primer/Cumulus_NetQ_Primer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/NetQ/deployment_guide/netq_primer/Cumulus_NetQ_Primer/</guid>
      <description>Cumulus NetQ Primer Cumulus® NetQ is a network operations tool set that provides actionable insight into and operational intelligence about the health of the entire Linux-based data center — from the container, virtual machine, or host, all the way to the switch and port. Working hand-in-hand with Cumulus Linux, NetQ enables organizations to validate network state, both during regular operations and for post-mortem diagnostic analysis. Running on Cumulus Linux switches and other certified systems — such as Ubuntu®, Red Hat®, and CentOS hosts — NetQ captures network data and other state information in real time, providing cloud architects and network operations teams the ability to operate with visibility into the entire network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>